

Dávid Szakállas

Software Engineer

Budapest, Hungary



+36306266558



https://szakallas.eu

@

david.szakallas @gmail.com

About me ———

Software engineer with experience in distributed data processing and back-end service development with strong preference for functional programming and type safety.

I have a M.Sc. in Computer Science Engineering and 5 years of experience in various areas ranging from backend development to data engineering.

Skills —

Big Data

Software Engineering

Functional Programming

Microservices

Databases

Data Analysis

Graphs

Cloud Platforms

Scala*5 Apache Spark*4.5 Git*4 Node.js*4 JavaScript*4 SQL*4 Python*4 Linux*3 Docker*3 Kubernetes*3 C++*2 Clojure*2 *

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Interests

I focus on developing distributed data ingestion and machine learning pipelines on cloud platforms using common open source technologies. I am keen on delivering automated, well-engineered solutions to mission-critical processes. I am a polyglot, having worked with several languages and prefer to use Scala, Python and JavaScript. I also have a basic foundation of statistics, machine learning and related technologies e.g., R, numpy, pandas, scikit-learn. I am a functional programming and type system enthusiast.

Education

2015 – 2018 M.Sc. in CS Eng. Budapest University of Technology and Economics

Thesis: Evaluation of openCypher graph queries with a local

search-based algorithm

2011 – 2015 B.Sc. in CS Eng. Budapest University of Technology and Economics

Experience

Oct 2017 – Feb 2020 Data Engineer Ekata (formerly Whitepages Pro) (Budapest)

Developing a mission-critical data ingestion application in Apache Spark. Developing platform libraries for file I/O and caching for Apache Spark. Orchestrating an ML pipeline with Apache Airflow, Kubernetes, Helm and Databricks. Developing a rapid ML feature prototyping application for data scientists

tists.

During my day to day work, I am using the following technologies and languages: AWS S3, Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, Docker, Jenkins, Git, Scala, Python, Kotlin, Databricks, XG-

Boost

Jan 2016 - May 2017 Software Engineer

RisingStack (Budapest)

Developing the monitoring agent in Node.js. Developing the back end microservices of the distributed tracing feature. Gaining experience in industry-standard distributed tracing technologies such as OpenZipkin, OpenTracing and Google Dap-

per.

Nov 2014 - Aug 2015 Technology Intern

Morgan Stanley (Budapest)

Developing an application for analysing logs of an internal messaging system for my Project Laboratory assignment using the ELK stack, Scala and relational DBs. Working on a financial application.

Other information

Public speaking

Oct 2018 Spark+AI Summit EU – Spark Schema for Free

March 2018 Budapest Clojure – Writing a Cypher query language in Clojure July 2017 NodeBP Meetup – Scripting a MIDI controller in JavaScript

Languages

Hungarian Native language

English Professional working proficiency

German Basic proficiency